Marlo Amaya

713-448-9676 moamaya@uh.edu 78728

Summary

Senior Technical Support Advisor and Mechanical engineering graduate with over 5 years in hardware and software troubleshooting experience, project experience using design and analysis techniques, and proficient use of programming and engineering applications such as MATLAB and SolidWorks.

Education

UNIVERSITY OF HOUSTON - BACHELOR OF SCIENCE - MECHANICAL ENGINEERING - DEC 2017

- Minor: Mathematics GPA: 3.0

Professional Development

TEXAS BOARD OF PROFESSIONAL ENGINEERS - ENGINEER-IN-TRAINING - OCT 2017

- Texas EIT Number: 61655

Experience

IOS SENIOR TECHNICAL SUPPORT ADVISOR; APPLE INC, AUSTIN, TEXAS - JUN 2015 - PRESENT

- Mentor incoming Tier 1 advisors through Listen to Learn procedures.
- Finished in top 5% nationwide in first quarter in role, based on customer satisfaction and issue resolution.
- Partner with engineering groups to resolve undocumented issues or safety captures on mobile devices.

IOS AND MAC+ TECHNICAL SUPPORT ADVISOR; APPLE INC, HOUSTON, TEXAS - JUN 2015 - PRESENT

- Maintained a 95% average customer satisfaction rating in 2017 with 6 months at 100%.
- Consistent top performer within multiple teams in the college organization
- Selected to transition to Tier 2 support within first month in full-time pro organization.

ADVANCED REPAIR TECHNICIAN; BEST BUY INC, PEARLAND, TEXAS - AUG 2012 - JUN 2015

- Performed repairs on electronic devices ranging from mobile to desktop computers.
- Assisted managers with training duties, and led department meetings.
- Modified repair process layout to reduce turnaround repair from 4 to 2 days.

MECHANICAL ASSEMBLER; TS3 TECHNOLOGY INC, STAFFORD, TEXAS – AUG 2011 - JUN 2012

- Assembled voting machines for the state of Oklahoma and control units for bi-fuel fracturing trucks.
- Provided feedback about building process to improve production, and improved voting machine production from 65 to 99 units per day.

Projects

CAPSTONE DESIGN – FIXED WING DRONE – APR 2017

- Led the prototype design using SolidWorks dynamics analysis.
- Implemented Design for Assembly processes to conduct frame build and controller casing design.
- Assisted with assembly of final prototype and interconnecting electronic components.

PROGRAMMING PROJECTS – DEC 2017

- Java Applet: Created GUI with Swing for graphing applet used to plot nodes or user input functions.
- Image Matching Program: Wrote python program used to scan through database of jpg files and match them to a query of images to display similar files in a table format.
- Analytics Project: Created MATLAB program used to scan database of handwritten digit images by implementing the k-means algorithm to display representative groups for each cluster and presented result to classroom of 25 students.
- Portfolio Page: Currently working on a portfolio page using HTML, CSS, and JavaScript to display my current and past engineering projects while also displaying my web development skills. Project can be found at <u>moamaya.github.io</u>